Robert Houghwout Jackson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Legal File, 1919-1962 (Box 59-188)
  - Justice Department
    - Attorney general
      - National Labor Relations Board, prosecution of officials for lobbying
      - Neutrality Act, application to cargo vessels
      - Neutrality Laws Unit
      - New York City Bar Association Judiciary Committee, New York, N.Y.
      - Office of Production Management
      - Oklahoma v. Woodring
      - Patents and defense production
      - President's Committee on Civil Service Improvement
      - President's power in foreign relations
      - Press releases
      - Proclamation of a national emergency, 27 May 1941
      - Report, Justice Dept., annual, 1941 (Box 93)
      - Selective Service Act
        - Conscription and conscientious objectors
        - Seizure of plants
      - Subversive activities and investigations
        - Christian Front sedition investigation
        - Coordinated Federal Bureau of Investigation, military intelligence, and naval intelligence program
        - Criticisms of Federal Bureau of Investigation methods
        - General
      - Sunshine Anthracite Coal Co. v. Adkins
      - Suspension of writs of habeas corpus
      - Tax immunity of cost-plus defense contracts (Box 94)
      - Townsend, Newman A.
      - Von Werra, Baron Franz
      - Waldenburg, Stefanie von Hohenlohe
      - Wallace, Henry Agard, document on economics
      - White House, miscellaneous memoranda
      - Wiretapping controversy
        - Justice Dept. and wiretapping
        - Legislation
        - Miscellany
        - Rhode Island investigation
        - War Department involvement
      - Zapp, Manfred, and Guenther Tonn, deportation of
  - Nuremberg War Crimes Trial, *Microfilm shelf no. 22,796 (Box 95, Reel 1*)
    - Pretrial material
      - Appointment of Jackson as United States chief of counsel
        - Congratulatory letters
        - Executive order
      - Declarations of intent to punish war criminals
      - Diary kept by Jackson, 27 Apr.-19 Nov. 1945, (2 folders)
      - German labor for reparations
      - London Conference, London, England
        - Miscellany
        - Press coverage
        - Protocol file
          - Final agreement, 8 Aug. 1945
          - Jackson's personal protocol of draft agreements, (2 folders)
          - Preliminary drafts of agreement, (4 folders) (Box 96, Reel 2)
          - Suggestions re protocol
          - United States alternative proposal
        - Publication of International Conference on Military Trials by State Dept., (2 folders) (Box 97, Reel 3)
        - Stenographic notebooks kept by Elsie Douglass
      - Reaction to report to the president
      - Report to the president, 7 June 1945
    - Office files, United States chief of counsel (Box 98, Reel 4)
      - Adherents to the charter
      - Allied Control Council directive 35 (sentences of International Military Tribunal)
      - Belgium
      - British delegation
      - Chief prosecutors' meetings
      - Collaborationists
      - Correspondence
        - Cables between Jackson and Nuremberg office after his return to United States
        - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
        - Public reaction to trial
          - May-Sept. 1945, (5 folders)
          - Oct. 1945-Mar. 1946, (7 folders) (Box 99, Reel 5)
          - Apr.-Sept. 1946, undated, (5 folders) (Box 100, Reel 6)
          - Rechberg, Arnold
        - Supreme Court
      - Czechoslovakian delegation
      - Dean, Gordon E.
      - Defendants
        - Furnishing of evidence to
        - International Military Tribunal rulings on defense applications
        - Miscellany
        - Named in indictment
        - Notice to (Box 101, Reel 7)
        - Potential
      - Defendants Information Center
      - Defense counsel
        - Selection
        - Speeches (fragmentary, not part of record)
      - Denmark
      - Documentary records of trial
      - Donovan, James B.
      - Donovan, William J.
      - Dulles, Allen W.
      - Evidence analyses
      - Executions, 16 Oct. 1946
      - Exhibits (Box 102, Reel 8)
        - Clerk's list of
        - Correspondence regarding
        - "The Nazi Plan," official documentary motion picture no. 3054-PS
      - Financial matters
      - Finland
      - French delegation
      - Gartner, Murray
      - Gisevius, Hans Bernd
      - Grand Mufti of Jerusalem, Haj Amin El-Husseini
      - Headquarters Command, I.M.T. (Provisional)
      - Horsky, Charles A.
      - Horthy, Nicholas
      - International Military Tribunal
        - Indictment
        - Judgment (Box 103, Reel 9)
        - Meetings between judges and chief prosecutors
        - Miscellany
        - Motions presented to
        - Orders and rulings
        - Personnel
        - Rules of procedure
      - Interrogations
      - Jackson, Robert H.
        - Billet at 33 Lindenstrasse
        - Biographical clippings
        - Miscellany
        - Notes
        - Official trips, summary
      - Jackson, William E.
      - Katyn Forest, Poland, massacre
      - Law library (Box 104, Reel 10)
      - Local trials
        - Austria-Hungary
        - Norway
      - Memoranda, reports, and points of law
        - Aggressive war, Horsky memoranda on
        - Aroneanu article on crimes against humanity
        - Asylum for refugees
        - Conspiracy, notes on
        - Denazification
        - German law
        - Individual responsibility
          - Report on Karl Haushofer
          - Kelsen memorandum
        - Miscellany, (2 folders) (Box 105, Reel 11)
        - Rules of warfare violation
        - Soviet policy
        - Superior orders
        - Treaties
        - War guilt
      - Miscellany
      - Norway
      - Office of Military Government (U.S.)
      - Palace of Justice, architectural plans
      - Personnel
        - Applications and recommendations, (2 folders)
        - Awards, decorations etc. (Box 106, Reel 12)
        - Miscellany
        - Navy
        - Office of United States Chief of Counsel staff, (2 folders)
        - Requirements
        - Rosters
        - Staff organization
        - Telephone directories
      - Poland
      - Press coverage of trial
        - German press
        - Surveys, (4 folders) (Box 107, Reel 1**)
          **Microfilm shelf no. 22,872
      - Pretrial planning
      - Psychiatric and personality studies of Nazi leaders
      - Public relations
      - Publications See also Container 117, same heading (Box 108, Reel 2)
        - The Case against the Nazi War Criminals, 1946
        - Foreword in Temple Law Quarterly
        - Nazi Conspiracy and Aggression, 1946
          - Distribution
          - Preparation
        - Suggested foreword for Charles Alexander's photographic volume on Nuremberg, 26 Mar. 1946
      - Radio broadcasts, 1945-1946
      - Reports
        - Final report to president, 7 Oct. 1946
        - Progress reports
      - Social file
      - Speeches (Box 109, Reel 3)
        - Jackson's opening speech, 21 Nov. 1945
          - Correspondence relating to
          - Publication of
        - Jackson's closing speech, 25 July 1946
          - Drafts and final speech, (2 folders)
          - Notes and correspondence
        - Rudenko's opening statement
      - Staff meetings (United States) (Box 110, Reel 4)
      - State Department
      - Stimson, Henry L.
      - Subsequent trials, (3 folders)
      - Summation by prosecution, notes for
      - Sweden
      - Telephone and teletype conversations, transcripts
      - Trial briefs (Box 111, Reel 5)
      - Trial planning
        - Anticipated defense arguments
        - Defense case
        - Prosecution case
      - Trial sidelights
      - Truman, Harry S.
      - United Nations organization
      - United Nations War Crimes Commission
      - United States forces, European theater
      - USSR delegation
      - Vatican
      - Visitors
      - Visual presentations
      - Wheeler, Burton K.
    - Posttrial material (Box 112, Reel 6)
      - Allocution of Pope Pius XII on International Penal Code, 3 Oct. 1953
      - Army mailing list for books on Nuremberg
      - Bormann, Martin
      - Codification of Nuremberg law by United Nations organization
      - Correspondence
        - A-C, (2 folders)
        - D-V, (5 folders) (Box 113, Reel 7)
        - W-Z (Box 114, Reel 8-9)
      - German war criminals, clippings
      - Goebbels, Joseph, publication of diary
      - International Military Tribunal for the Far East
        - Judgment, (2 folders)
        - Rulings
      - Japanese war crimes prosecutions (Box 115, Reel 10)
      - Katyn Forest, Poland, massacre
      - Motion pictures
        - "The Nuremberg Trial," Pare Lorentz
        - "The Sealed Verdict," Paramount Pictures, 1948
      - Notes and extracts relating to war criminals and international law
      - Printed matter
        - Articles
          - 1945-1948, (2 folders)
          - 1949-1962, undated (Box 116, Reel 11)
        - Clippings
        - Monographs, 1945-1952, (3 folders)
      - Publications See also Container 108, same heading (Box 117, Reel 12-13)
        - "Authentic Recorded Highlights of the Nürnberg Trial," Binghamton, N.Y.: Epoch Records, 1948
        - Documents published in Temple Law Quarterly
        - The Hadamar Trial, edited by Earl W. Kintner, foreword by Jackson, (2 folders)
        - Jackson, William E., articles by
        - Nuremberg Diary, by G. M. Gilbert
        - The Nürnberg Case As Presented by Robert H. Jackson and Other Documents, 1947
        - Proposed articles re Nuremberg (Box 118, Reel 14)
        - The Trial of the Major War Criminals before the International Military Tribunal, Nuremberg, 14 November 1945-October 1946
        - Viking Press digest of Nuremberg documents
      - Records of the United States chief of counsel
        - Preliminary inventory by the National Archives
        - Transferred to the National Archives
      - Speeches by trial staff members
      - United Nations War Crimes Commission, (2 folders)
  - Supreme Court (Box 119)
    - General
      - Appointment of Jackson as associate justice
        - Congratulatory letters, (5 folders)
        - Nomination and confirmation hearings
        - Tydings, Millard, opposition
      - Court letter to Owen J. Roberts on his retirement
      - Disqualifications and absences, 1941-1953
      - Habeas corpus (Box 120)
      - Index to cases (alphabetical) See Container 248
      - Luncheon for Justice Thorleif Ferdinand Schjelderup of Norway
      - Marshal's office
      - Miscellany
      - Opinion notes
        - Habeas corpus See also Containers 177, No. 4, and 178, Nos. 20, 22, 31, and 32
        - Picketing
      - Photographs
      - Requests for material
      - Rules of the Supreme Court
        - Admiralty Rules Commission, 1946-1953
        - Condemnation cases
        - Federal rules of civil procedure
        - Proposed changes, 1947-1949
        - Rules revision project, (4 folders) (Box 121)
      - Salaries and annuities for federal judges
      - Second Circuit, 1947-1954 (Box 122)
      - Staff lists
      - Printed matter
    - October term 1940
      - Cases
        - Goldman v. United States; Shulman v. United States; Goldman v. United States, Nos. 962, 963, 980
    - October term 1941
      - Chief justice
      - Cases
        - Bridges v. California; Times-Mirror Co. v. California, Nos. 1 and 3
        - United States v. Bethlehem Steel Corp.; United States Shipping Bd. Merchant Fleet v. Bethlehem Shipbuilding Corp., Nos. 8-9
        - Indianapolis gas cases, Nos. 10-13
        - Commercial Molasses Corp. v. New York Tank Barge Corp., No. 14
        - New York, Chicago & St. Louis R.R. v. Frank, No. 15
        - Edwards v. California, No. 17
        - National Labor Relations Bd. v. Virginia Elec. & Power Co.; National Labor Relations Bd. v. Independent Org. of Employees of the Va. Elec. & Power Co., Nos. 25-26
        - Duckworth v. Arkansas, No. 43 (Box 123)
        - Irving Trust Co. v. Day, No. 51
        - District of Columbia v. Murphy; District of Columbia v. deHart, Nos. 58-59
        - Meilink v. Unemployment Reserves Comm'n, No. 61
        - White v. Winchester Country Club, No. 63
        - Southport Petroleum Co. v. National Labor Relations Bd., No. 67
        - Duncan v. Thompson, No. 78
        - Merion Cricket Club v. United States, No. 83
        - United States v. Carolina Freight Carriers Corp., No. 197
        - D'Oench, Duhme & Co. v. Federal Deposit Ins. Corp., No. 206
        - Howard Hall Co. v. United States, No. 210
        - Miles v. Illinois Cent. R.R., No. 272
        - Jones v. City of Opelika; Bowden v. City of Fort Smith; Jobin v. Arkansas, Nos. 280, 314, and 966
        - Muncie Gears Works v. Outboard, Marine & Mfg. Co., No. 323
        - Anderson v. Abbott See Container 128, No. 3, No. 497
        - United States ex rel. Tenneesee Valley Auth. v. Powelson, No. 500 (Box 124)
        - Holland v. Lowell Sun Co., No. 529
        - Gregg Cartage & Storage Co. v. United States, No. 535
        - Swift & Co. v. United States, No. 595
        - Pence v. United States, No. 665
        - Skinner v. Oklahoma, No. 782
        - State Tax Comm'n of Utah v. Aldrich, No. 814
        - Bakery & Pastry Drivers Local 802 v. Wohl, No. 901
        - Wickard v. Filburn See Container 125, No. 59, No. 1080
    - July special term 1942
      - Cases
        - Ex parte Quirin, Orig. and Nos. 1-7
    - October term 1942 (Box 125)
      - Chief justice
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers
      - Cases
        - Schneiderman v. United States, No. 2
        - United States ex rel. Tennessee Valley Auth. v. Powelson, No. 3
        - McNabb v. United States, No. 25
        - Washington Terminal Co. v. Boswell, No. 28
        - Williams v. North Carolina, No. 29
        - Wickard v. Filburn (continuation of case no. 1080, October term 1941), No. 59
        - United Carbon Co. v. Binney & Smith Co., No. 71 (Box 126)
        - National Labor Relations Bd. v. Indiana & Mich. Elec. Co., No. 73
        - Endicott Johnson Corp. v. Perkins, No. 142
        - United States v. Oklahoma Gas & Elec. Co., No. 171
        - United States ex rel. Marcus v. Hess, No. 173
        - Interstate Commerce Comm'n v. Inland Waterways Corp., No. 175
        - Pendergast v. United States; O'Malley v. United States; McCormack v. United States, Nos. 183 and 186-187
        - Terminal R.R. Ass'n v. Brotherhood of R.R. Trainmen, No. 218
        - Martin v. City of Struthers, No. 238
        - Securities & Exch. Comm'n v. Chenery Corp., No. 254
        - Spies v. United States, No. 278
        - Jones v. City of Opelika; Bowden v. City of Fort Smith; Jobin v. Arizona, Nos. 280, 314, and 966 (October term 1941) (Box 127)
        - De Zon v. American President Lines, No. 436
        - Douglas v. City of Jeannette, No. 450
        - Corn Exch. Nat'l Bank & Trust Co. v. Klauder, No. 452
        - Helvering v. Griffiths, No. 467
        - Murdock v. Pennsylvania For additional material see same container, Nos. 280, 314, and 966, Nos. 480-487
        - United States v. Swift & Co., No. 529
        - Interstate Transit Lines v. Comm'r, No. 552
        - Bowles v. United States, No. 589
        - West Virginia State Bd. of Educ. v. Barnette, No. 591; (2 folders)
        - Interstate Commerce Comm'n v. Columbus & Greenville Ry., No. 628 (Box 128)
        - Detroit Edison Co. v. Commissioner, No. 675
        - Boone v. Lightner, No. 698
        - Virginia Hotel Corp. v. Helvering, No. 766
        - Hirabayashi v. United States, No. 870
        - Yasui v. United States, No. 871
    - October term 1943
      - Chief justice
      - Cases
        - Simpson & Co. v. Commissioner, No. 1
        - Anderson v. Abbott (continuation of case no. 497, October term 1941), No. 3
        - Securities & Exch. Comm'n v. C. M. Joiner Leasing Corp., No. 24
        - Magnolia Petroleum Co. v. Hunt, No. 29 (Box 129)
        - McLean Trucking Co. v United States, No. 31
        - Consumers Import Co. v. Zosenjo, No. 32
        - Northwest Airlines v. Minnesota, No. 33
        - Federal Power Comm'n v. Hope Natural Gas Co.; City of Cleveland v. Hope Natural Gas Co., Nos. 34-35
        - Dodson v. Commissioner; Harwick v. Commissioner, Nos. 44-47
        - Demorest v. City Bank Farmers Trust Co.; Dyette v. Title Guarantee & Trust Co., Nos. 52 and 227
        - Mercoid Corp. v. Mid-Continent Inv. Co.; Mercoid Corp. v. Minneapolis-Honeywell Regulator Co., Nos. 54-55 and 58-59 (Box 130)
        - J. I. Case Co. v. National Labor Relations Bd., No. 67
        - Prince v. Massachusetts, No. 98
        - Davies Warehouse Co. v. Bowles, No. 112
        - Helvering v. Lane-Wells Co., No. 115
        - District of Columbia v. Pace, No. 117
        - Sartor v. Arkansas Gas Corp., No. 232
        - Goodyear Tire & Rubber Co. v. Ray-O-Vac Co., No. 262
        - National Labor Relations Bd. v. Hearst Publications, Nos. 336-339
        - Order of R.R. Telegraphers v. Railway Express Agency, No. 343
        - Pollock v. Williams, No. 345
        - United States v. South-Eastern Underwriters Ass'n, No. 354
        - Yakus v. United States; Rottenberg v. United States, Nos. 374-375
        - Ashcraft v. Tennessee, No. 391 (Box 131)
        - Hazel-Atlas Glass Co. v. Hartford-Empire Co., No. 398
        - Cramer v. United States (continued as No. 13, October term 1944), No. 406
        - Tennessee Coal, Iron & R.R. v. Muscoda Local 123, No. 409
        - United States v. County of Allegheny, Pa., No. 417
        - General Trading Co. v. State Tax Comm'n, No. 441
        - Arenas v. United States, No. 463
        - Chicago, St. Paul, Minneapolis & Omaha Ry. v. United States, No. 482
        - Wisconsin Gas & Elec. Co. v. United States, No. 565
        - Thomas v. Collins See also Container 132, No. 14, No. 569
        - International Harvester Co. v. Wisconsin Dep't of Taxation; Minnesota Mining & Mfg. Co. v. Wisconsin Dep't of Taxation, Nos. 620-621
        - Interstate Commerce Comm'n v. City of New Jersey, No. 767
        - United States v. General Motors Corp. See Container 133, No. 76, No. 962
    - October term 1944 (Box 132)
      - Chief justice
      - Cases
        - Nebraska v. Wyoming, No. 6 Orig.
        - Skidmore v. Swift & Co., No. 12
        - Cramer v. United States, No. 13; (2 folders)
        - Thomas v. Collins See also Container 131, No. 569, No. 14
        - Korematsu v. United States, No. 22
        - Herb v. Pitcairn; Belcher v. Louisville & Nashville R.R., Nos. 24-25 (Box 133)
        - Muschany v. United States; Andrews v. United States (continuation of case Nos. 711 and 726, October term 1943), Nos. 31-32
        - Tunstall v. Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen (continuation of case No. 779, October term 1943), No. 37
        - Keegan v. United States; Kunze v. United States (continuation of case No. 821, October term 1943), Nos. 39 and 44
        - Screws v. United States, No. 42
        - Western Union Tel. Co. v. Lenroot, No. 49
        - Barber v. Barber, No. 51
        - United States v. Associated Press; Associated Press v. United States (continuation of case Nos. 880-882, October term 1943), Nos. 57-59
        - Spector Motor Servs. v. McLaughlin, No. 62
        - Northwestern Bands of Shoshone Indians v. United States (continuation of case No. 915, October term 1943), No. 63
        - United States v. Waddell, Holland & Flinn (continuation of case No. 925, October term 1943), No. 65
        - Wallace Corp. v. National Labor Relations Bd.; Richwood Clothespin & Dish Workers' Union v. National Labor Relations Bd., Nos. 66 and 67
        - Ex parte Endo, No. 70
        - Armour & Co. v. Wantock, No. 73
        - United States v. General Motors Corp., No. 76
        - New York v. United States (continuation of case No. 996, October term 1943), No. 83 (Box 134)
        - Williams v. North Carolina, No. 84
        - New York v. United States (continuation of case No. 996, October term 1943), No. 86
        - Chase Sec. Corp. v. Donaldson, No. 110
        - State Farm Mut. Auto. Ins. Co. v. Duel, No. 115
        - Webre Steib Co. v. Commissioner, No. 148
        - Connecticut Light & Power Co. v. Federal Power Comm'n, No. 189
        - Barr v. United States, No. 287
        - United States v. Willow River Power Co., No. 312
        - Commissioner v. Wheeler, No. 354
        - Malinski v. New York, No. 367
        - Colorado Interstate Gas Co. v. Federal Power Comm'n; Canadian River Gas Co. v. Federal Power Comm'n, Nos. 379-380
        - Ambassador, Inc. v. United States, No. 446
        - United States v. Ballard, No. 482
        - Market St. Ry. v. Railroad Comm'n, Nos. 510-511
        - Hunt v. Crumboch, No. 570 (Box 135)
        - Radio Station WOW v. Johnson, No. 593
        - Sinclair & Carroll Co. v. Interchemical Corp., No. 656
        - United Bhd. of Carpenters & Joiners v. United States, Nos. 666-668 and 674-675
        - Jewell Ridge Coal Corp. v. Local 6167, United Mine Workers, No. 721
        - Bridges v. Wixon, No. 788
    - October term 1945
      - Cases
        - In re Yamashita; Yamashita v. Styer, Nos. 6l Misc. and 762
        - Nippert v. City of Richmond, No. 72
        - Anderson v. Mt. Clemens Pottery Co., No. 342
    - October term 1946
      - Chief justice
      - Docket book
      - Law clerks
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and papers
      - Cases
        - Freeman v. Hewit (continuation of case No. 40, October term 1944), No. 3
        - Champlin Ref. Co. v. United States, No. 21 (Box 136)
        - Bruce's Juices v. American Can Co., No. 27
        - Angel v. Bullington (continuation of case No. 540, October term 1945), No. 31
        - Harris v. United States, No. 34
        - Ballard v. United States, No. 37
        - Hickman v. Taylor, No. 47
        - Rothensies v. Electric Storage Battery Co., No. 48
        - Haupt v. United States, No. 49 (Box 137)
        - Everson v. Board of Educ., No. 52; (2 folders)
        - Bethlehem Steel Co. v. New York State Labor Relations Bd.; Allegheny Ludlum Steel Corp. v. Kelley, Nos. 55 and 76
        - National Labor Relations Bd. v. A. J. Tower Co., No. 60
        - Federal Communication Comm'n v. WOKO, Inc., No. 65
        - Crane v. Commissioner, No. 68
        - Interstate Commerce Comm'n v. Mechling, No. 72
        - Securities & Exch. Comm'n v. Chenery Corp.; Securities & Exch. Comm'n v. Federal Water & Gas Corp., Nos. 81-82 (Box 138)
        - Independent Warehouses v. Scheele, No. 83
        - Trailmobile Co. v. Whirls, No. 85
        - Gulf Oil Corp. v. Gilbert, No. 93
        - Adamson v. California, No. 102
        - Ex parte Fahey, No. 133 Misc.
        - Louisiana ex rel. Francis v. Resweber, No. 142
        - Koster v. (American) Lumbermens Mut. Casualty Co., No. 206
        - Land v. Dollar, No. 207
        - Patterson v. Lamb, No. 229
        - United States v. Standard Oil Co., No. 235
        - Craig v. Harney, No. 241 (Box 139)
        - Walling v. Nashville, Chattanooga & St. Louis Ry.; Walling v. Portland Terminal Co., Nos. 335-336
        - New York v. United States; Hildreth v. United States; Atchison, Topeka, & Santa Fe Ry. v. United States, Nos. 343-344 and 354
        - Sioux Tribe v. United States, No. 368
        - Fay v. New York; Bove v. New York, Nos. 377 and 452
        - Adams v. United States, No. 457
        - Greenough v. Tax Assessors, No. 461
        - United States v. Smith, No. 498
        - Cook v. Fortson; Turman v. Duckworth, Nos. 531-532
        - Fleming v. Mohawk Wrecking & Lumber Co.; Raley v. Fleming, Nos. 583 and 512
        - United States v. Bayer, No. 606
        - Packard Motor Car Co. v. National Labor Relations Bd., No. 658
        - Fahey v. Mallonee For additional material see Container 138, No. 133, No. 687
        - United States v. Walsh, No. 718